MANSVINI AGGARWAL

Full-Stack Software Engineer

+91-9650438090 @ coderspecial@gmail.com & https://www.linkedin.com/in/mansvini/ P Delhi, India

SUMMARY

A problem-solver with 2 years of experience in leading businesses looking to leverage communication skills as a software/full-stack engineer. Coding since the age of 11 with experience in building complex modules optimised for performance, deploying projects, and scaling them using best practices. B.Tech in Electronics & Communications Engineering.

FIND ME ONLINE



Portfolio

https://mansvini.netlify.app/



PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Open Source Contributor

Zero To Mastery 11/2021 - Ongoing

A global open source playground for the coding community

- Collaborated with community managers and developers from around the world on GitHub and Discord.
- Contributed to ZTM Job Board project using SCSS, HTML & JavaScript.
- Participated in the Animation Nation Hacktober challenge.

Co-founder

Health Blis 12/2019 - 09/2021

A B2B startup in the pharma industry

- Handled end-to-end design and development of websites while regularly <u>updating and maintaining</u> them.
- <u>Tested, deployed and observed content management systems on production servers</u> to get a better **User Experience**.
- Communicated and collaborated with 200+ stakeholders to build a supply chain that <u>led to an ROI of 16% within 3 months</u>.

Core Team Member

Honest Farmer 06/2018 - 03/2019

A startup to supply produce from farms to customers within 24 hours of harvesting

- Solved the problem of drain water irrigation and food traceability by building the world's fastest 100% traceable food supply chain.
- Worked with the core team while managing a team of 6-8 people.
- · Brainstormed solutions creatively while handling operations.
- <u>Acquired 200+ customers</u> from a single locality through communication and marketing which converted to 30% regular customers.

Information Technology (IT) Intern

Oil & Natural Gas Corporation (ONGC) 06/2017 - 07/2017

- Learnt the functioning of ONGC, SAP ERP, and SAP ABAP.
- Built an Online Quiz Software on SAP using the ABAP language.

Embedded Systems Intern

IBM 06/2016 - 07/2016

- Learnt about the practical applications of Embedded Systems.
- Built the project <u>Data monitoring using GSM Module</u> with AVR AT Mega 16, sensors, GSM module and C++.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

JavaScript(proficient) **TypeScript** SSH C++ (prior experience) Node.js **Parcel** Server-Side Rendering AWS Webpack **Code Splitting** Security Serverless Load Balancing **Code Analysis** Heroku Blockchain **Performance Optimizations**

PROJECTS

Smart Brain using ML API

https://mansvini.github.io/smartbrainfrontend/
A web app built using React for the frontend,
Express as RESTful API and Postgresql as a
relational database. Stores hashed passwords
securely using cryptography. Uses JSON Web
Token (JWT), Redis (non-relational database) for
session management, and Docker. Backend
deployed on AWS (Lambda & EC2).

Robofriends

https://mansvini.github.io/RobofriendswithRedux/ A Progressive Web App (PWA) built with React JS and Redux which fetches users (robots) from an API. It is performance-optimized and integrated with CircleCI for CI/CD, Jest for testing, and Tachyons for styled-components.

EDUCATION

Computer Science

Zero to Mastery Academy

10/2021 - 04/2022

B.Tech-Electronics & Communications (ECE)

Guru Gobind Singh Indraprastha University 09/2014 - 08/2018

VOLUNTEERING

Volunteer

The Art of Living

06/2018 - Ongoing

- Taught about the importance of mental health to 250+ youth.
- Worked with a team and mentors to conduct events for various social causes.
- Continuously organised 10+ workshops for 150+ participants.